Translation: HollaBella Cthulhu Cat Zesheng Fat Ming Sixteen Xiao Jing Ze Yu
Proofreading: Big Heart Row 16 HollaBella Machsel Zhang
Timeline: Huang Peach Messenger, Lang Lang Li, HollaBella, and Old Man, Mahsele Zhang
Welcome to follow Sina Weibo @马赫塞勒张 for the first time to get the video download address with embedded Chinese and English subtitles and translator annotations
The translations used in this subtitle when referring to the original text of the "Bible" are based on the "Mandarin Chinese Union Version" ("God" version)
The Psychological Significance of the "Bible" Story Third Lecture "Genesis" Chapter One Summary-God and Authority Hierarchy by Jordan B. Peterson
I have been looking forward to this lecture for a long time
It’s not that I don’t care about other lectures
What I want to explore tonight is the story of the Bible
Something that shocked me in particular
Especially the story of Cain and Abel
Hope to tell this story later
The length of the story is unbelievable
Only about 10 to 11 lines
Hardly said anything
However, I found these short stories
But can reveal endless truths
I am not sure what caused this
Given that I decided to use as rational as possible
To analyze this problem
I think this stems from the "Bible" story for a long time
Intense refinement
In a nutshell
The information in the Bible story is so compressed and refined
Make it difficult for people to come up with a corresponding explanation
It’s hard to come up with an explanation that convinces me
I think those old stories
The "Bible" story we discussed before is very old
One thing you can be sure of for these stories is
All the memorable parts of the story have been remembered
to some extent
This is the same as Richard Dawkins
The memetic theory is similar
This is why I always feel that Dawkins
More mysticism
He would become Karl Jung
Because the theories of the two are incredibly similar
Memetic theory and the prototype of the collective subconscious
Are very similar views
But I think Jung’s views are much more profound
Indeed Jung thought more thoroughly
Because Dawkins tends to think of memes as a kind of brainworm
It can erode the minds of many people
However I don’t think Dawkins
Give enough attention to this view
He made a joke the last time he talked to Sam Harris
They talked about
Is there a possibility of memes
As religious memes
Changed the evolutionary history
They immediately avoided that topic
With a burst of laughter
They decided to stay away from that topic
It's fun for me
Condensation of "Bible" story
Makes me very confused
It must be with people
Can't forget that the Bible story is related
This question can be empirically tested
I don’t know if anyone has done a similar experiment
You tell the unworldly two stories of equal length
One contains the prototype theme and the other does not
Wait until three months later
Let’s observe which story people remember more deeply
This kind of experiment is simple and straightforward
I haven't started the experiment yet, maybe I will try it in the future
But in short
I am very excited about this lecture
Because I will have the opportunity to talk about the story of Adam and Eve
And the story of Cain and Abel
I hope I can tell these two stories tonight
It's better to tell the story of Noah and the Tower of Babel
But given the progress in the past
I don't have much hope for this
But it doesn't matter
Hardship
Before you start
I want to explain
The psychological meaning of the concept of God
I thought a lot about this
Because this series of lectures gave me a chance and forced me
Keep thinking
I have a hypothesis for the concept of the Trinity
This assumption is basically like this
The concept of the Trinity first vividly embodies
"There is a deep cognitive structure that enables consciousness
"There is also consciousness itself"
I mean the concept of "Holy Father"
Similar to the "transcendental structure that enables consciousness"
the concept of
This is part of our birth
It is our structure
You can think of it as
The product of long-term evolution
I think it's not completely related to
Conflicting views in the first chapter of Genesis
At least from a metaphorical point of view
It is difficult to interpret the literal meaning of the story of the Bible
For example, it emphasizes day and night
But if you understand it as
Clock on the 24-hour clock
It’s weird that day and night alternate
When you think about the construction of the universe
The literal meaning of the Bible is not reasonable
There is one more point
Many early Christian fathers
For example, Origen
As early as 300 AD
These ancient "Bible" stories should be regarded as metaphors of wisdom
Should not be rigidly understood word by word
There is a saying
People who established Christian doctrine
All fundamentalists who strictly follow the literal meaning
This is totally wrong in history
Some of them used to be like this
Still so
But this is not the point
Because most of them are not fundamentalists
People two thousand years ago
Not a fool
They are fully capable of understanding
Metaphorical content
They also know that fictional stories are to some extent
Can be regarded as an abstraction
This kind of abstraction can reveal the truth that some documentary works cannot express
Unless you think fictional works can only be pastime
This idea is ridiculously wrong
Good to continue
In terms of the concept of the Father
This concept refers to in order to be able to understand the world
You must have a priori cognitive structure
I mentioned this last time by Immanuel Kant
Kant opposed the following argument
"All the information we receive in our lifetime
"Only input from sensory data"
The reason why Kant criticized this argument is
And his criticism is completely correct
Sensory data cannot be parsed without a priori structure
You can’t extract from sensory data
Used to parse the structure of sensory data
This is simply impossible
This has also been confirmed
Since the 1960s
The first failure of artificial intelligence
Is the best example of this view
Because scientists started looking forward in the 1960s
People will have practical autonomous robots
And artificial intelligence
People didn’t realize that
This kept them stagnant until the 1990s
The difficulty of the problem of "perception"
Beyond anyone's understanding at the time
When you observe the world around you
Seems to have seen various objects
Actually what you see is not an object
But tools
The neurobiological principle of this phenomenon is clear
You are not observing the object and then speculating on its purpose
But after observing the purpose, we can see what we see
This is contrary to common sense
The key is no matter what people see
Is it an object or a tool with a certain purpose
You will see them when you look at the world around you
You think the action of "watching" is easy
Because things can be seen everywhere
As long as you turn your head, things appear in your vision
This idea is ridiculously wrong
The problem of "perception" is particularly difficult
We haven’t built an autonomous robot yet
One reason is
Although we are a lot better than in the 1960s
We found that you have to have a body first
Ability to think
more importantly
You have to have a body before you can observe
Because observation is essentially
Is the model of the material world
Mapped to the body pattern
It’s not that things existed here first
You see them and then you realize their existence
Then you evaluate them
Then you decide how to treat them
Finally you start
You can say that this is the
Mental processing and perception
But this is not the case
Like human eyes
Will map the light-sensitive signal to the spinal cord
Will leave a mark in the emotional system
So for example
People who are blind may still feel the facial expressions of others
In other words, patients with cortical blindness
Their visual cortex is damaged, usually caused by a stroke
They are physically invisible
But it can sense which hand the tester raised
When you show a picture of an angry or fearful face to the patient
Patients will be emotionally full of pictures
Skin conduction reaction
This is due to the following reasons
Assuming the world is composed of different patterns
In fact
Assuming these patterns
Propagate to you through electromagnetic signals or light
And after being replicated by the retina
Transmission along the optic nerve
Finally dispersed in the brain
Some of these patterns make up a conscious vision
Other modes only activate physical functions
For example, I look at this
What is the name of the bottle
I look at the bottle especially when I think about the bottle
I looked at the bottle
Bottle model
Activated the "squeeze" motion mechanism of my hand
Part of this perception process is to adjust my body movements
Including the "squeeze" movement of my hand
Make it the best way to perform grabbing actions
It’s not that I saw the bottle first in the process
Think about how to hold the bottle
That's too inefficient
But I use sports cortex to perceive the bottle
This process is independent of
Look at the conscious experience of the bottle
So anyway what I want to say is
There are countless similar phenomena
Rodney Brooks has a say in this
He is a robotics engineer
In the 1990s
He invented the Roomba sweeping robot and other things
This man is really a genius
Brooks first pointed out
In order to give the machine enough
Perception ability to work normally
Machine body
The perception ability should be built from the body
Instead of building down from abstract cognitive consciousness
Later this view was confirmed
Brooks in the 90s
Made many strange small mechanical devices
These devices have no actual brain
But it can behave like staying away from the light source
These devices can sense light
Their perception behavior is
The action of escaping from the light source
Perception is closely related to action
This is different from what people usually think
In short I mean
If you are not reified, you cannot know the world
Your current way of representation has gone through
It took about 3.5 billion years to take shape
This process presupposes a lot of death
Formed the concrete form you have today
This process has gone through various trials and failures
Just created a human like you
Have enough ability to deal with the complex world
To spend a relatively short 80 years of life
So I think maybe my idea is wrong
But I think this is at least a useful assumption
I think the concept of the Father is similar to
The birth of this view
There is an internal structure
Consciousness is born from it
This structure gives form to things
This idea is not necessarily right
But if this assumption is correct
It reflects what I described before
Factual truth
I also mentioned that I will
Holy Spirit and Son Concept
Especially in the form of Tao
As an active consciousness generated and used by internal structure
It not only conceives the world
We do imagine the world
At least imagine the world we see and experience
It also changes and adjusts the world
We undoubtedly did this
Partly with our bodies
Evolution makes our bodies suitable for these
This is why we have hands
And dolphins don't
Although they also have human-like large-capacity brains
But they can't change the world
Humans adapt to changing the world through evolution
Human words are an extension of hands-on ability
Our discourse system is
A well-developed motor skill
Generally speaking
The brain hemisphere you use to control language
It's also the hemisphere of your dominant hand
People said and gestured with their hands
You saw me too
We can sign language
Hand use and language use
Closely related
Partly because language is a kind of creativity
And the hand is also one of the forces that transform the world
A priori structure
Very closely linked
Also closely related to the concrete structure
I think this part explains
Why the classic Christian doctrine is more than
Emphasize the divinity of the Holy Spirit
Also emphasizes the divinity of the body
And this is even more difficult to understand
Because you are more likely to think
If you have religious thinking
You are more likely to think that there is something transcendent in your body
Not bound by a specific body
It will continue after death
And so on
But Christianity is especially
Emphasize that the body also has divinity
This view of "there is implicit structure"
Semi-patriarchal nature
The reason is complicated
But partly because it is a reflection of social structure
Is also a reflection of other things
And use awareness
Especially linguistic consciousness
The most important thing is to use sincere language
Able to construct the world in a "good" way
I think this is a powerful concept
especially
Sincere language can create good
This is a very fundamental moral proposition
I think this idea is difficult to refute
One thing I noticed is
Of course not only I noticed
There is no denying that there are many tragedies in life
Many people i met
For example, patients in my clinical treatment
Overwhelmed by misfortune in life
But I also often see
The person who can't get out of intrigue
This deception network often lasts for generations
Let them down
Deception can cause extreme pain
This pain will last a long time
This is common sense in clinical practice
Freud pointed out
Cause pain
Or a cause of mental illness and depression
It's a lie deliberately concealed
It's quite correct to think so
Jung bluntly proposed
Psychotherapy efforts
And huge moral effort
Including telling the truth is essentially the same
He thinks that both are one thing
Carl Rogers, another great clinician
He was a Christian missionary
Later he became a scientist
Rogers believes that sincere dialogue
Will produce clinical transformation
Of course in clinical treatment
One of the prerequisites for true transformation is
Doctors and patients are sincere
otherwise
How can you know what happened
You can’t do without knowing what the problem is
To solve the problem
And only the other party tells you the truth
So you know where the problem is
If you want to improve your relationship with others
You should think about this
If you don’t tell the people around you the truth
They won't know you
Maybe this is a good idea
Sometimes people lie for a reason
And not for trivial reasons
But you must also know
Unless you express the actual situation in good faith
You can't touch the real problem
If you can't reach the real problem
It is basically impossible for you to solve the problem
I'm still thinking about another thing
The more i think
This point of view becomes clearer
This view is
This view is partly
Let me think about how to start well
I have a friend who is also my business partner
Also my thesis collaborator
He is very smart
I told you about him before and he accused me of using
The word "dominant level"
The term is used for creatures like chimpanzees and lobsters
It might not matter
But maybe it’s not even suitable for chimpanzees
He said something very interesting
He sees the concept of superiority level as
Similar to the Marxist assumptions of the early 20th century
A projection in animal society
For example, "the chimpanzee mating level
"Advantage hierarchy
"It's built on power."
He believes that this view is actually a projection of a certain political ideology
His views troubled me for a long time
Because I have been using the term superiority level
After he told me this, I felt
Ah so annoying
Because what he said may be right
I spent a few months thinking about this problem
At the same time I am still reading Frans de Val
He is a primatologist
Still reading Jayak Panksip
An outstanding emotional neurologist
Unfortunately he just passed away
His "Affective Neuroscience" is very good and it mentions
The mice must play fairly
If it's unfair, the rats won't participate in the play
This is a shocking discovery
Because anything can prove
Specific examples of the origin of animal moral behavior
This is related to the evolution process
It is also the core of Panksaipu’s research
Can prove
Ethics that guide mankind
Not just the construction of sociology and paraphenomenism
But something more ingrained
And mice, if my god, they are just mice
You can't trust the mouse
But they also pay attention to fairness when playing games
Deval Discovery
Among the chimpanzees he studied
Savage orangutan ruled with an iron fist
Did not become a successful ruler
Because once the orangutan ruled with an iron fist leaks its decline
Will be despised and trampled by him
Chimpanzee companion torn to pieces
Will be divided by five apes
And a long-term orangutan leader
It rules the stable orangutan kingdom
They will be reciprocal to their "friends"
Orangutans also have friends
Their friendship can last a long time
When dealing with females and baby orangutans
They also take a lot of reciprocal behavior
Deval is a very wise man
I think this research is also basic scientific knowledge
Because you have to know
Factors that contribute to dominance in male dominance levels
Sorry for using the term "male dominance level"
Maybe it’s better to call it “authority”
Or to say it scaryly "ability"
It's better to think so
This factor is not just based on
Above barbaric power
I still think
The following view is a very absurd and dangerous political view
That is, "in a law-abiding society
"The male hierarchy is based on power."
This view is very absurd
You just have to think about the last month
Not long
You can understand how absurd this view is
Most authority
Are restricted by ethics
They are more restricted than other lower ranks
We can also understand this in business management books
Because in general
The pressure the manager receives from his subordinates
More pressure than the subordinates get from the manager
This is not surprising
Do you want to manage 200 people
Are you sure
This is a chore
I know the boss is usually annoying
Because you have to care about what the boss thinks
And your boss may be a bossy person
And bossy bosses are generally not particularly successful
But managing 200 people is really not a joke
Shoulder this responsibility and authority
You must always be careful
Because people will keep pointing out your mistakes
So it's not that
You are in a higher position in the hierarchy
The moral restraint on you is less
Of course if you are a psychopath
That's another matter
But the psychopath has to be in a different hierarchy
Keep running
Because people will soon see through psychopaths
Once they are ruined
Their tricks cannot continue to succeed
all in all
Behavior patterns are very interesting
Imagine how sexual selection is done
We know sexual selection
Is a very, very powerful biological force
Although after Charles Darwin created the theory of evolution,
Biologists have ignored sexual selection for more than 100 years
Only focus on natural selection
Biologists don't wait to see sexual choices
Because it will change the concept of mind
Join the evolution process
Because sexual selection involves the process of selection
Now imagine that there is a male hierarchy
People at the top of this hierarchy
Than those at the bottom
Easier to reproduce successfully
This is especially true for men
Number of female ancestors of a person
Will be twice as many as its male ancestors
I don't want to do calculations
Although this sounds unreasonable
But you can look through your own family tree
The actual situation happens to be
There are twice as many female ancestors as male ancestors
Is due to the possibility that women will have offspring on average
Twice as much as men
Any male who reproduces
Tends to multiply
And the other group of males have zero reproductive opportunities
An average male who reproduces has two offspring
Of course, a male who has no chance of reproduction has zero offspring on average
An average female who reproduces has one offspring
In other words, in a person’s pedigree
There are twice as many female ancestors as male ancestors
This matter is not trivial
Imagine something like this
Men choose a capable admirer
I can't say that this person is dominant
He is given authority and respect
Say so
Just like election
Can be democratically elected
But at least an election that everyone agrees
Or at least
"We still have to keep him right now, let’s not kill it."
This is also a form of election
Is a form of tolerance
What happens next is
Women as far as they are concerned
Will select partners from the top of the male hierarchy
So there are two factors
Drives human sexual selection
A long-term evolutionary process
One is aimed at men by men
Election of who can get a position with greater breeding opportunities
The second is women from
The tendency of men to start selecting partners at the top of the male dominance hierarchy
This works well in every culture
Even if you evened out between men and women
Socioeconomic inequality
Such as the situation in Northern Europe
You can't effectively reduce women
The tendency to select a partner from the top of the male hierarchy
You don't want to lower
Women are smart
Why don't they go
To pursue relationships with relatively successful men
Why don’t they let men define themselves first
What is success
It makes sense
If you want to figure out who is the best male
Why not let men compete on their own
No matter what kind of competition
The final winner
Is the best male by definition
How else would you define it
Why i say this
The reason is I think
Election of male dominance in the process of human evolution
And the victory of sexual selection
Have complex interactions
If it's true, it's no small matter
Because of this
With evolution
Males will be more and more optimized towards the apex of male rank
Because men who are not good at this way have no offspring
So it must be
But then there is more than one level system
Because it will produce a bunch of different levels
You will ask whether there are commonalities between different levels
This is a reasonable question
At least the different levels are not completely opposed
If you are relatively successful in a hierarchy
Then you are in another hierarchy
The possibility of success will be greater
This is a right
A good definition of general intelligence or IQ
Intelligence is actually a factor in women choosing men
Of course men also choose women like this
But men are more pressured to choose than women
IQ can help you
One of the factors to climb different dominance levels
Because it is a universal mechanism for solving problems
Another factor to some extent
Conscientiousness
There is evidence that women tend to choose conscientious men
It's reasonable, why not
Such men are trustworthy and work hard
These are advantages
Then you will think
Men have adapted to climbing the male dominance hierarchy
They adapted to climb
Various grade systems
Then you will think that there are so many different attributes
Can be put into practice
Can be reified
These attributes can increase successful summit
The possibility of
In the end you will think
As people get used to it
They will start to understand
What makes up this pattern
This becomes a multidimensional ability
Abstract representation
Such as the abstraction of virtue
All of these are not generated at will
But firmly rooted in the physiology
I think this view is difficult to refute
I have such a habit when I think
When i think about something
It will take a long time to figure out if your opinion is wrong
I will try to start from every possible angle
To examine whether this view is tenable
If it’s hard to get a foothold, then I’d rather discard it
Turn to thinking about better ideas
I spent a long time trying to figure out
What is wrong with this view
Because in my opinion it's quite unbreakable
This view is like this
Like when people watch a movie
And so on, when you read novels
Obviously people are good at
Distinguish between the pros and the villains
Villains are generally bad guys
It's the kind of deliberate deliberate for authority and high position
But people who fail in the end are generally like this
So he is a good negative example
If you take a child to watch a movie that is a party
He soon knew that he should not be a villain
And quickly focused on the positive person
this means
Models of good people in fictional works
There is an affinity with the child’s perception
I told my son when he was young
The movie I took him to see
Sometimes it’s really scary
What I told him was
I never tell him don't be afraid
I don't think this is good advice for children
I'm talking about focusing on the hero character
I kept emphasizing this sentence with him
He looked very attentively and was often scared
Because some movies are really scary
Then he focused on good people and looked forward to it
You know it's like this when watching movies
Generally speaking, you want good people to win
Why do you think this way? Where does this idea come from
Have you noticed how deep-rooted this idea is in your heart
You line up to buy movie tickets to see how good people win
It's hard to understand
But people think it’s so self-evident that they don’t notice
This is actually a huge mystery
So is the following idea unreasonable
That is, we have concluded such a collective conclusion for thousands of years
What is the best good person
What is the worst bad guy
Archeologically speaking, I regard this opposition as hostile brothers
Like Christ and Satan or Cain and Abel
Hostile brothers are a very common mythological theme
These are the prototypes of good people and bad people
For example, Satan’s definition is the worst bad guy
These are just conceptually speaking, the definition of Christ is
Is the best one can be
I am discussing this issue from a psychological and conceptual sense
Given our imagination and ability to invest in fictional works
Love for fiction and ability to dramatize things
And the love of heroism stories, disaster stories and good and evil stories
I can't think of any other explanation for this
This part drives the formation
The concept of "the evolution of the concept of God"
More specifically it drove the evolution of the concept of the Trinity
At least in part
God is an abstract ideal incarnation of its formation
Incarnation of ideal
Separated from any concrete avatar or ruler
There is also such a rule in the "Bible" story
I mentioned before that when people started to move existing rulers
When confused with abstract ideals
The country immediately fell into tyranny
Everything collapsed instantly
This is actually very complicated
What people found
It's actually hard to find
That is you have to put abstract concepts
Take it out of any specific power structure
And treat it as
An abstract concept
But it is also a real thing
It exists because it governs your behavior
And everyone’s actions including the sovereign
The monarch must also be responsible for this abstract ideal
You see this is really incredible
What did people think about 5000 years ago
You can notice something
Often appears in the Old Testament of the Bible
Let’s take the Israelis as an example
Whenever the king of Israel becomes omnipotent
The true God will appear and crush them
Then the whole country fell apart
For hundreds of years
I think what I want to teach us
We have not been able to clearly understand
This is still very implicit in the narrative
We haven't been able to figure out why this is the case
I find it difficult for you to ignore this argument
Ok we talked about this before
The concept of the Trinity is like this
The Holy Father should be said to be the basic structure of consciousness
A dramatic performance
Or the concrete structure of consciousness
Next is the Son, it is consciousness
But in a specific historical form
This point about the image of the Son is quite interesting
There is also a form of consciousness
Can be seen as the inner spirit
These psychological thoughts must have a source
They have history
Didn't come out of thin air
They are derived from the dream hypothesis
And artistic imagination
After a long period of evolution
Clarified as consciousness
We worked hard for a long time
Chimpanzees who only looked at each other
Developed to human
We all have a faculty called consciousness
It took a long time
Really long
And it must have gone through many stages in the development process
I really like a point of Jean Piaget
He is a developmental psychologist
He insisted that before children understand concepts
To be able to practice and dramatize these concepts
Merlin Donald is a psychologist at Queen's University
Based on this point of view, I have written a few interesting books
The book discusses how imitation
The important role played by human development of advanced cognition
This view is that we put our ideas into practice
We abstract the idea
And make it clear before
This is a very strong point
I can't think of any better explanation
If you observe the children, you will understand
Think about it when the children play house
What are they doing
Children will play the role of father or mother
The interesting point here is
You will think this is too cute too
This little girl is imitating her mother
But not really
It's not like that
When your child imitates you
Actually quite annoying
You move your arms and they follow you
If you move your head, they still follow
No one likes this kind of direct imitation
But this is not what children do when they play
In fact, they observe the mother
Behavior in countless instantiation scenarios
And extract from it
A spirit called "mother"
This is the mother
Image in a variety of specific behaviors
Children internalize this model
And express it in the abstract world
It is very complicated
You actually did this when you played Jiajia
Or when playing tea and taking care of your doll
It’s not that you saw your mother taking care of a doll
That's not the case
But you have enough wisdom
To extract this concept and visualize it
There is no doubt that this child
Working hard to achieve this ideal
She didn't set the doll on fire
Of course it’s not like this
Generally we don’t encourage children to do this
So you can see this ability in children
And we also know
If the child does not to a large extent
To participate in this dramatic and hypothetical game
They cannot socialize properly
This is indeed a key factor in developing self-understanding
It can also help individuals develop the ability to get along with others
When you were young
Especially when he is about four years old
You build a shared virtual world with the outside world
For example, we played house together
Then you are in that shared virtual world
To play a shared role
This is a very advanced form of cognition
very complicated
This is the same thing I have observed and Piaget
Jung Floyd and Merlin Donald
These amazing observers have discovered
How cognition develops
They are very aware of this concrete imitation
And dramatic abstraction forms the foundation
So that more advanced abstract cognition can emerge from it
How could it not be this explanation
Obviously before we develop a complete mind
We mainly rely on the body
So long before we could understand certain ideas
Can put these concepts into practice
Just like chimpanzees will practice the following concepts
If you are the chimpanzee leader
Your behavior must be sensible
Otherwise you will be torn to pieces
You can also observe from the wolf
When wolves fight for power
They will blow their hair at each other
Make yourself look huge
Will growl and bark
Will become very vicious
The inferior wolf will turn his body over to show weakness
Put your neck back up, body language like this is to show
"Yes, I'm so useless
"You can kill me if you want."
The wolf in the dominant position will say
"Yes, you know you are pretty useless
"I can tear your throat open but tomorrow
"We might use you when we hunt moose
"So I will spare your life"
They don’t think like this
They don’t have such thinking ability
But they put this idea into practice as a mode of behavior
If you are an anthropologist or behaviorist
Go and observe the behavior of the wolf
You would say they seem to act according to the law
I usually get confused about this because I think
Are there rules for wolves?
The so-called law of law is when we
What is constructed when accurately expressing a behavior pattern
We observe a stable behavior pattern
Then express it accurately, which is called the law
But it’s not a rule for wolves
That's just a stable behavior pattern
We behave like wolves or chimpanzees
Has lasted for tens of millions of years or even hundreds of millions of years
Until we have the ability
To change our behavior pattern
Tell it with stories or images
We can express it precisely as a set of moral codes
It took longer
I spent a long time explaining these
I know some of them I have talked about before
But these are really important
Some people are putting pressure
Especially those social constructivists
They think the existing moral system is random
Morality is relative human behavior
There is no fundamental biological basis
Ethics
First of all I think this is very dangerous
Because this theory means what you want people to become
What a person can become
You better be careful with people who have such thoughts
Secondly, there is too much evidence
Explain that this view is wrong
We really shouldn't think like this anymore
This is why I’m from an evolutionary perspective
Part of the reason to criticize this view
There is growing evidence that
Moral and ethical standards are at least the most important ones
They have not only evolved and will be
Reemerged in children’s dramatic games
We have to take this seriously
Part of what we are doing now
There is a concept like this, at least in part
The Father Go and Let the Son
From the chaos to generate an indwellable order
At the same time I also think there may be
Closer to the real situation
There is an interesting point about men
Men are more criminal than women
This does not seem to be sociocultural
Part of the reason is that men’s criminal impulses
Peak testosterone secretion at around 14 years old
This impulse will rise quickly
And stay active until around 27 years old
The standard penalty theory says so
If you don’t know, let me explain
Suppose there is such a habitual offender
He keeps getting into trouble
Then you can put him in jail until he is 28 years old and then release him.
It's not that you are going to reform him or something
Only after he was 28, his passion for crime disappeared
Because his criminal impulse curve peaked around 15
And then began to decline around 27 years old and disappeared
By the way, men usually get married at this age
Settled and stabilized
It's also interesting
The development of the male creativity curve is the same
The curve peaks when testosterone begins to secrete
And then began to decline around 27
The two curves are very, very close
This is really interesting
The part about creativity
I am very interested
Because in all respects youth is the source of creativity
Look at this sentence carefully
If you strip it away from its religious context
You will see it is talking about older people
Use young people to generate innovative ideas
And use it to update the world
That's right
We don’t know how many inventions and discoveries humans have
By children and teenagers
Found by the blind cat and dead mouse
Because young people are more adventurous
Less restricted by their existing knowledge structure
They will not be so conservative
So I think it makes sense
And very important
It also means that if you are a father
There is such a meaning in it
This is one thing you should encourage your son to do
Because the father acts as an encouragement
It is obvious
And encouragement means
Go out, kid, face the unknown chaos
And the chaos hidden beneath everything
Go fight it because you can do it
You are as powerful as chaos itself
You have to recognize this and do something useful
Make your life better
And make people around me better
You can do it
This is what you should tell young men
What to say to young women is more complicated
Because they are facing
More complicated situation
Their lives are more complicated
But it's absolutely correct to tell your son that
I recently discovered one thing
Especially since the seven or eight months since I gave the lecture
I found that my audience is mostly young men
I told them a lot about truth and responsibility
I think they are "generating order from chaos"
The factors behind
I see young men eager for words like this
These words are different from the topic of "rights"
Far apart
It is the counterpart of "right"
Life is difficult and chaotic
Definitely a challenge
No wonder you can choose to shrink in front of life
Because life is fatal and not child's play
Or you can face it calmly
Try to make some changes
Which option do you think is better
If you tell someone
You can do it
This is how people are
If you cheer up and face it bravely
You will find out soon
You can really do it
I think this is a very core religious message
And is deeply rooted in this idea
This is the point I have been conveying to you
The knowledge itself is also generated like this
There are many unknowns
You know nothing about them
Generally when you encounter something unknown
Your first reaction is never thinking
But with an expression of horror like this
This is your first reaction to something absolutely unknown
What you encounter is beyond the scope of understanding
The unknown scares you
It is beyond your understanding
You can't perceive or understand it
But you still have to face it
The way you face it is to stay still
The snake monster in "Harry Potter"
That's how to deal with children
As soon as I see the snake demon children, they can’t move
This is the terrifying snake of chaos hidden beneath all things
You can't move when you see it because you are a prey
But while you are afraid, you are also curious
This is the first stage of your contact with the absolute unknown
A mixed emotion frozen in fear and curiosity
This is also reflected in the story about dragons
Dragons are terrible creatures living underneath
It is entrenched with gold and maidens
This behavior is also very strange for reptiles
But this is a symbolic representation
It represents the predatory nature of the unknown
But the unknown can also
Generate new information
You can think of it as a characteristic of humans
Because we are prey
But we are also very adventurous
We are very good predators
We occupy such a weird cognitive position
One thing we learned from this is
If we muster up the courage to face the unknown fear
Although it is frightening
But you will continue to get huge rewards
This truth is too real
Have such a view
At the beginning of time, God extracted the inhabitable order from the chaos
There is a metaphor under this concept
This metaphor is a very old concept
God has encountered a monster like Leviathan
This is a chaotic beast like a python
Leviathan is one of the commonly used names in the Old Testament
In addition to Leviathan, there is another called Behemoth
Yes it's the name
There is such a point of view that should come from
Mesopotamians think that whether God is
The image of the Father or the Son
He is the beast facing the terrible unknown chaos
And cut it to pieces
And will distribute its fragments to the people to raise them
Here you can also see a metaphor of hunting in it
But it’s actually more profound
So it’s absolutely unknown
It's something you don't understand
The unknown is something outside of your campfire lighting
The longer it is, the thing outside the tree
Because we used to live on trees
It lurks somewhere you don't know
What's out there
Crocodile snake raptor
Big cats
All the creatures that can eat you
But go out and find out what is useful to you
Maybe you didn't kill the snake when you went out
But gave the snake nest
You will become very popular soon
This is what you deserve
Put it this way, it will boost your chances of reproduction
And we are the descendants of these people
We will have
The concept of "the world is built like this"
This is deeply rooted in our minds
Very, very deeply below the surface cognition
Deeply embedded in our limbic system
This is a very old part of the brain
Existed for 60 million years
Even billions of years or more
It is a very very old brain structure
So the first thing we do is
We go to meet the unknown world
The way to meet with
How is God described in the Bible
At the beginning of time, the order that can be accommodated is extracted from the chaos
The approach taken is the same
I won’t tell you about other things for now
So we will first practice
Then we observe how others practice
Then you start to describe them
This is a story right
Maybe you still admire some stories
After a while you have collected a lot of stories
Then you can describe what they are
Can you describe them precisely as a pattern
This is what Nietzsche first summed up
Because before Nietzsche
He took the lead in achieving many achievements
Really amazing
Before Nietzsche some people thought
You think first and then act
Many people love to think so
But you know this is obviously pure bullshit
Because you can't imagine how impulsive you can be
You often start acting without thinking
Although sometimes the effect is pretty good
"Seeing first and then thinking
Is the idea of ​​"do something next" true?
I'm not like this anyway
As far as I know no one is like this
Actually people don’t do it at all
Especially when people are very emotional, they will act first
Nietzsche clearly expressed a point
Our thinking for thousands of years is
Conceived from our behavior
When philosophers put forward these ideas
They are not creating new ideas
They are just telling stories about human nature
These ideas already exist
Already rooted in our minds
Has already appeared in our behavior pattern
Nietzsche is a genius
This is just one of his countless extremely genius discoveries
You can think so too
First you encounter the unknown
And you act on it
Then you will dream about your behavioral reaction
The same when you watch a movie
You will talk about it later
Of course once you start talking
This will in turn affect your dreams
Your dreams will also affect your behavior
Not all causality is one-way
It's not like that they circulate each other
But it still originated from the unknown through our bodies and imagination
Expressed by us
This is the basic mode of the generation of wisdom
You can easily see some clues from the perspective of evolutionary interpretation
You have the actual body first, right
Then you can imagine
Imagination is the abstract expression of the flesh
Language
This is how we step by step
Because of our ability to imagine
Before we could speak
At least in theory
This is an illustration from my book "Map of Meaning"
This is unknown
Basic representation
It is semi-spiritual
Because the Rinku part looks like a bird
It is also semi-materialized
Because the parts on the ground are like snakes
When you don't know what's there
This is what you think it will look like
When you face the unknown
Your body will respond naturally
You know very well that when you are alone at night
Maybe for some reason you are a little upset
Maybe it’s because you just watched a horror movie
It happens that there are some strange noises in other rooms
It's dark outside
You'll know if you try it someday
Then you are so nervous
Then you think about or turn on the light
See what's going on in the room
Don't do this yet
You just need to open the door a little bit
Then put your hand in and try
Look at your imagination
Will tell you what's in the room
Then you can immediately remember when you were three years old
Lying alone in bed facing the dark fear
I recently read a book about dragons
There is a very interesting hypothesis
The author did such a job
Sorry i don't remember his name
He tracked the universality of the image of "dragon" worldwide
It turns out that its universality is extremely surprising
He thinks it actually gathers predators of various primates
Predator is a strange category
There are crocodiles and lions inside
But they will eat you
Have nothing in common
So it is a functional category
This picture is
Image representation of the functional category of predator
His predator theory is like this
If you are a monkey
Maybe a bird will kill you like an eagle
If it’s not an eagle, it’s okay to assume it’s a cat
Because they will climb trees and give you a fatal blow
If it’s not a cat
You come under the tree
The snake will kill you
Or snakes can climb the tree
Snakes kind of like climbing trees, the result is the same
Basically, you can think of it as the archetype of "tree cat snake"
Or "tree cat and snake bird"
These are definitely things you want to avoid
You never want to run into any of them
In addition, the dragon can breathe fire
This is very interesting
Because fire is man’s best friend
Also the worst enemy
We have learned to use fire proficiently for a long time
It may be 200 or more than 3 million years old
There is a man named Richard Langham
It should be Langham
He recently wrote a book
I should remember his last name correctly
He wrote a book about when humans learned to cook
Humans learned to cook about 2 million years ago
Cooking improves the utilization of food calories
Think about what a chimpanzee is like
They look ugly
Looks like a large bowling pin
Looks very fat and strong and short
Their intestines are almost three hundred miles long
Because they have to digest the leaves
You can try to run into the forest
Sitting and chewing leaves for a day
See what happens to you
There is no heat in the leaves
So chimps need to spend every day
I remember it was almost eight hours for chewing
Because what they eat has no nutritional value
So they need a huge digestive system
To extract anything valuable from it
However, at a certain moment, human beings suddenly opened up and thought that they couldn't bear it anymore.
Let's cook something to eat
So we traded the digestive system for the brain
How successful
I think it also makes us more attractive
The point here is this
This is the basic prototype of the unknown
I really like St. George's version of the story about the unknown
Pretty cool
Saint George lives in a castle
This castle is half collapsed
Partly because of the appearance of the dragon
This is an immortal dragon
It often disturbs everyone
This kind of thing always happens
Because the eternal dragon will always be ready
Add to our already difficult life
Saint George is the hero who bravely faced the dragon
He freed the girl from the claws of the dragon
I think this is a pretty straightforward story
It's about the sexual attraction of masculinity
This masculine person has the courage to face the unknown
In my opinion this is a very obvious biological characterization
This is a very old story
May be the oldest story we can record
The Creation Epic of Mesopotamian Mythology
"Enuma Elish"
Basically telling the story
I bet some of you movie lovers
Especially those obsessed with
The kind of fancy superhero movie guy
You may be in the past ten years
Have watched this St. George's story hundreds of times
And you are not tired of it
Because this is the core story of mankind
So this is unknown
You use your body’s instinct to face it
You show existential fear
And extreme curiosity
It’s like the so-called "unknown unknown"
What is the name of the politician under Bush?
By the way Rumsfeld
I think the reason this term is so popular is
Rumsfeld interprets this prototype very well
"Unknown unknown"
And "known unknown"
The dragon here belongs to the "unknown unknown"
You have to know that you are facing
How to react when "unknown unknown"
Because it might give you a fatal blow
You can't use ignorance as an excuse
Because it is fatal
It won't work
Human beings are such a creature when they are at a loss
They have to know what to do
This is contradictory
We must prepare for everything
We are always on guard
Get ready to face everything
This is a kind of high tension
But in a state of concentration
And it can strengthen your consciousness
This kind of human reaction loop may be permanently opened
Because we know that people are mortal
No other animal knows this
Sometimes i feel
Our stress response circuit is always open
This explains partly
The reason for our strong consciousness
So you will encounter "unknown unknown"
Then you will have the real world
The unknown
For example, some mysteries in your partner
You will feel this way when you argue
who are you
You are not completely unknown to me
Because i still know you a little bit
But now what you show
Completely foreign to me
This part is what we know
There are those who know
The known things here are given a symbolic representation
in my opinion
In the form of the patriarchy of the masculine deity
And the unknown things you encounter are given a feminine form
We will not explain much in depth yet
But if you are interested
You can take a look at my "Map of Meaning" lecture series
You can read this book
I think it sums up the religious archetype very well
I studied for a long time
I feel it can be applied to Jung's ruler
It maps well to Joseph Campbell’s theory
But many of Campbell’s theories came from Jung
This can also be said from the perspective of biology and evolution
As far as I know it is like this
At least in my judgment
There are many examples of cross-validation
Okay, let’s go back to the dominant hierarchy
Let's take a look at this picture
You may know that I am very obsessed with lobster
Because i found something about it
I really felt empowered when I discovered this
I have a lot of research on functional neurochemistry
Because I have studied alcohol addiction and drug abuse
To study alcohol
You must fully understand the brain
Because alcohol can penetrate all parts of the brain
It affects every neurochemical system
So if you want to study alcohol
You need general knowledge of neurochemistry
I have been studying neurochemistry for a long time
I am very fascinated by a book
The title of the book is "Anxiety Neuropsychology"
The author is Jeffrey Gray
This book is really a genius but it is also very difficult to understand
I don’t know how many references are used in this book
At least one thousand
Gray really read these references
Even understood them
Then he integrated these references into his book
Want to read "Anxiety Neuropsychology"
You must thoroughly master functional neurochemistry
Animal Behavior Motivation and Emotion and Neuroanatomy
This book is very difficult to understand but it is really rich in content
It took 40 years for psychologists to really understand it
One thing I learned in it is
Between human and animal neurochemistry
Have strong continuity
Really incredible
It makes evolution
Seems obvious
I do think it is obvious
But there are other reasons I will talk about later
I think when the environment is so complex that it exceeds our ability to understand
Random mutation and natural selection are
The only way to solve the problem of how to adapt to the environment
I think all you can do is produce countless variants
Because what will happen next moment is never known
Most of these variants will die because they are failures
One of the pair reproduces
The surrounding environment is constantly changing like a giant snake
You never know what it will do next
The best you can do
These 30 variants may survive
But 28 of them will die
For insects, the odds are much higher
Let's talk about lobster
They will fight for dominance
I think "dominance" is the correct way to understand
Lobsters do not have empathy and sociality
It really wins by strength
The interesting thing about lobster is
When a lobster wins
It stretches to appear taller
It shows higher because of winning
It’s like advertised
The neurochemical system that makes it stretch
Can affect serotonin
Do you think who cares what's the point?
I tell you what is the point
It is also a chemical substance affected by human antidepressants
If a person is depressed
Like a defeated lobster
Would curl up like this and seem to say
I am too weak and the world is too dangerous
I want to give up fighting
You give people an antidepressant and they will hold their heads up
Ready to fight the world again
If you give a lobster that has lost a fight a dose of serotonin
They will stretch again and fight again
From 350 to 600 million years ago on the time scale of evolution
We differentiated from creatures like lobsters
But our neurochemicals are no different
This is also the authority hierarchy
Another proof of importance
It has survived since the lobster era
When the lobster first appeared on earth
There is no tree on earth
This means these hierarchies that I have been talking about
Older than the appearance of trees
There is a self-evident truth like this
From the perspective of Darwinism
"Reality" is made up of things that last the longest
Because it has the longest time
To put pressure on natural selection
We learned that about 60 million years ago
We live in the forest after evolution
This is one-tenth the length of the hierarchy
The evolution of the hierarchy
Pressure of natural selection
I think this view is beyond doubt
How it did it and what does it mean
These issues can be discussed
But this biological continuity is amazing
This theory is not what I found but what I read
The interesting thing is when I review this theory
Talked about it with my graduate students
I often take them out for breakfast
They like to argue very much
Always want to be better than others
And also very smart
Before this becomes a bit annoying
In about six months
Every time someone does better than others
They will hold their heads up and hold their hands in a pliers
Really interesting
It’s amazing that lobsters do this kind of action
About Lobster
Another interesting thing is
Suppose you are a lobster who has been in power for a long time
But you are a little old
There is a young lobster that beats you up and down
You will become very depressed
Your brain is the ruler's brain
But not very developed because you are just a lobster
You lost the fight
What will you do
the answer is
Your brain will decline
Then you will grow a subordinate brain
This is worth thinking about for the following reasons
the first
If you have suffered a major setback in your life
You will know how it feels
It seems that life is better than death
If lucky
You will be reborn
Maybe you will be reborn as another person
This is what people with post-traumatic stress disorder experience
Their brain undergoes permanent neurological transformation
Then the world they live in will be more
More dangerous
We also know
If you suffer from traumatic stress disorder or depression
Your hippocampus shrinks
It will die and become smaller
Sometimes it can grow again
Your hippocampus shrinks and your amygdala grows
The amygdala increases emotional sensitivity
The hippocampus inhibits emotional sensitivity
So if you fail miserably
The hippocampus shrinks and the amygdala enlarges
If you come out of failure
The hippocampus becomes bigger again
Antidepressants can assist this process
But the amygdala never gets smaller
This is another lesson we learned from lobster
This is shocking
But the interesting thing is that you can understand the behavior pattern of lobster
"I know what this poor crustacean is going through"
Let's talk about mice
This is the study of Jayak Panksepp
He was the first person to find that mice can laugh
You might be wondering what is good for research
Why spend 50,000 research funds on giggling mice
He discovered the playful brain circuit of mammals
This is a major discovery
Just like discovering a new world
There are playful brain circuits in the mammalian brain
It is formed by nature rather than acquired socially
Here is where the biological mechanism comes into play
So what did Panksepp study about mice?
He found
If you isolate a young rat from its mother
It will die
Even if you feed it
Give it a suitable environment it will still die
If you rub it with the eraser at the end of the pencil
It won't die
Because mice need love to live
The same goes for human babies
In the Romanian orphanage after the Ceausescu disaster
We can observe this phenomenon
Those orphanages are full of abandoned babies
Because Ceausescu insists on pushing
All Romanian women must keep getting pregnant
So the orphanage is full of abandoned babies
Many abandoned babies don’t even have names
They are like goods being stored
They are given warm home food
Appalling
But many babies are still dead
Most abandoned babies die before one year old
The surviving baby suffers from permanent dysfunction
Because as a human, you must have physical contact
it's necessary
You must have the experience of playing
This is also necessary
This is one of the necessary conditions for neurodevelopment
And you have to participate in the play fairly
Otherwise your child will be out of touch with society
He cannot notice the subtleties of social interaction
To some extent socializing is continuous play and reciprocity
So what did Panksepp find in the mouse
He noticed the male rat
Especially young male rats like fighting very much
They will fight like humans
They will pinch each other
My goodness
That mouse just lost and lost ten points
You can try some baby mice
Then see if they want to play
You can tie a spring to the mouse
They will try to escape
By measuring how long they pull the spring
I can see how much they want to escape
You can estimate how motivated they are
Then you will find
One without any worries
Thriving rat
Still try hard
Enter the place where it used to play
It will make an effort
In other words, this mouse is motivated
Two mice playing together
They will play like dogs
If you know a little bit about dogs
You know what that is like
They have this kind of action
Human children do the same
If you play with your wife occasionally
You will do the same
My poor wife
She was young and her brothers and sisters were older than her
So at the age she should play when she was young
She doesn't play enough
I used to be like this
For example, if you take a pillow
Then shake it like this three times
Means optimistic
I want to throw you a pillow
So I will throw one, two, three
She will be very surprised and puzzled
The expression is like saying what are you doing
I finally taught her the meaning of this action
There is another thing
Sometimes when we are playing
She will walk towards me like this
I will hold her wrist
Put her fists together joint to joint
She used to be very angry because of this
I think so
You have to do this
Open your hands
She doesn't know how it should be
When she was just a "little mouse"
She doesn't play enough
You let the mouse out to play
We assume that one of the mice
One-tenth the size of the other one
This larger mouse will win
Because one-tenth of the weight of a mouse
Enough to make you a winner instead of a loser
Rats beat mice
Then the rat becomes the dominant rat
Next time I play
Mice have to invite rats to play
The rat just stayed leisurely
The mouse emerged from nowhere
Find ways to invite rats to play together
Rats will condescend to play with him
But if you repeatedly group them together
Unless the rats let the mice win in a third of the time
Otherwise the mice will not invite the rats to play together
Panksepp discovered this phenomenon
I really felt enlightened after reading his research
It's amazing
First of all because this is in line with Piaget’s point of view
"Human morality can arise from play behavior"
Formed an analogy
This is really amazing
But on the mouse
This concept is established on the level of fighting
Rats are very social animals
They must learn how to get along with other rats
In the fight for majority dominance
They don’t want the fight to become bloody and violent
Suppose you are Rat One and I am Rat Two
In the fight for dominance
We tore each other to pieces
Three mice will make a profit
This is obviously not a good strategy
If we can peacefully
It would be better to seek common ground while reserving differences
Anyway, Panksepp found that mice can play
They not only play but also play fair
And they like fairness
He also found a little bit cool
If you give young rats a drug for attention deficit disorder
Ritalin
It inhibits mice from playing
This is worth thinking about
Why do we give children in school
Using amphetamine
Because children need play to grow up
But adults will say no to play
Don't play around
In my opinion this is "oppression"
Don't let them frolic
It's ok
Give them amphetamines
It inhibits the play circuit in their brain
Then the problem is coming
Panksepp Discovery
If you don’t let young male rats play
Their prefrontal cortex will not develop normally
I didn't expect it
You are restraining them from becoming mature
Otherwise what do you think
I think this is really worth pondering
These are a few wolves fooling around
just kidding
These wolves are fighting for authority
Professionally
Some wolves are pretending
Sociable wolf
Tend to not hurt other wolves in power struggles
The reason is obvious, hurting each other is too dangerous
They have other ways to prove
Who should give orders is authority
These chimpanzees are doing the same
If i remember correctly
This is a great photo
Because of this chimpanzee
By the way, orangutans hate snakes
So for example
If you have a chimpanzee who has never seen a snake
You show it a snake
It won't be happy
It will immediately run away from the snake
If you take an anesthetized chimpanzee
Sent to a room with many chimpanzees
These chimpanzees will stay far away
Then stared at the anesthetized chimpanzee
They don't like this either
If you put a huge snake in a chimpanzee cage
Even if the chimpanzee has never seen a snake
They will also go far
Then stare at the snake
Wild chimpanzee
If you see a huge snake
They will stand there and make a cry
Seems to be saying
"My God, there is a big snake."
It is indeed the case
I will tell you why later
They stand farther away and make this kind of call
It means "Oh my God, look at this snake"
Then they will stand there for about 24 hours
Just stare at that snake
Snakes are really a super stimulus for chimpanzees
It's really interesting
This chimpanzee seems to have learned how to take this dead snake
To scare other chimps
This is also one of the ways it builds authority
Snake is a threat
If I were the orangutan beside this chimpanzee
I will take this threat seriously
Because snakes are not a joke
You can see the same thing in these monkeys
I don't remember what kind of monkey this is
Their behavior is radical
By the way
Recent research shows
Higher order primates
Snake detection circuits are naturally formed in the brain
This is not acquired
This is more profound than acquired
Psychologists knew that
Use pictures of snakes or snakes in condition experiments
Scared the subject
Much faster than pictures with guns or guns
We can quickly understand the fear of snakes
Also for spiders
Then people will think
Maybe we are prepared in advance
Build fear of such animals as snakes or spiders
More recent research shows
It's not just ready
But we have this kind of detection circuit innate
Why not
This is indeed a problem
It's not surprising
Unless you think human beings are just a blank slate
If you really think so
how to say
You should have crawled out of the 16th century
This is my opinion
This view is really outdated
Simply wrong
You can think of this behavior as a dominance hierarchy
But wolves also pursue credibility and ability
Chimpanzees don't like cruel tyrants
Then we will discuss it as a hierarchy of authority
The picture shows how it started to develop
These girls are discussing the family environment
How to do things properly
How to share turns etc.
They are discussing the hierarchy of authority
If you are good at mutual benefit
Sometimes you are an authority
Sometimes others are authority
It's fair right
These boys are doing the same thing
You can see them smiling
This looks like an attack
Not too careful
Paranoid
People who don't like humans
Confuse this with aggressive behavior
They will prohibit students from doing this in school
For example, when my child is in school
This is a long time ago
They are not allowed to touch snow
In case they throw snowballs
This is a terrible thing
So i told my son
He can use snowballs at will
Hit any teacher in the back of the head
As long as he is willing to bear the consequences of this behavior
I don't know if he really did it
But he was obviously very happy with the idea
I'm very happy for him
Children need to play like this
They really need to do this
This makes them civilized and polite
They need to learn to be civilized and polite when they are two to four years old
Because if before the age of four
They still didn't learn to be polite
Then don't expect them to learn
This is a terrible statistic
But in the literature related to development
It is well proven
There are many aggressive two-year-olds in the literature
Many boys
If they are over four years old, they are still aggressive
They probably stay in this state for their entire lives
They have no friends to be rejected
They are more likely to become
Anti-social lawless juvenile delinquent and go to jail
Your child needs to socialize between two and four years old
Especially aggressive boys need
Most aggressive two-year-olds are boys
By the way, being offensive is not socializing
There is a more abstract way of expressing this matter
What i want to say is
The hierarchy of authority is from
Emerges from the matrix of a potential game-like
This is what makes Jean Piaget outstanding
This view is extremely clever he came up with
He is very interested in the biological origin of morality
He traced the origin of play
And the formation of morality in play
This view is very clever
It's incredible
Because morality is built from the bottom up
Piaget is a constructivist
He is also a social constructivist to some extent
He underestimated the important role of biology here
But this does not prove that his theory is wrong
Theory for him
It is not difficult to add a biological support
We now have enough biological knowledge
Can do this well
In fact, such as Panksepp
Can already recognize the play circuit in the human brain
This is a good start
Play has been with mankind for so long
So that we all have a brain circuit
Designed for play
This is a very very old topic
This is the abstract concept of the game
Then you got a
The most extreme abstraction and expression such as this picture
Even the terrain of the game is fictitious
Of course we have largely migrated to
In these fictitious environments
Fictional books, movies, video games
These are extensions of the same thing
Exercises for real life
Sometimes becomes a reality
These are also manifestations of the Father
I like these expressions
I also like the concept of triangles
I don’t know why God wears a triangle hat
This shape is a bit strange
But I think it is related to the concept of pyramid
And also and
Authority hierarchy related
I think this is why the Egyptians
Will put Pharaoh in the pyramid
I know there are other reasons besides this
But I think there are some reasons
Related to the concept of this hierarchy
This is obviously a guess
I don't want to be too precise
But I can’t help thinking that the two are related
That picture is the pattern on the back of the US dollar bill
I like this picture very much
It resembles the Eye of Horus in Egyptian civilization
The idea is like
At the top of the hierarchy
Is no longer
Part of this hierarchy, right?
So if you climb high enough in the hierarchy
What will happen is you will get an ability
It is the result of your climbing in this hierarchy
Can separate you far enough from this system
After that you are no longer part of it
So you can move in all kinds of hierarchy
What you really master is
attention
From a mythological perspective
It seems that it can be extracted from the chaos
Of the source of the applicable order
The concept of spoken language rivals
Is vision and attention
Such as the creator god of Marduk Mesopotamia civilization
From Mesopotamian civilization
Appear in the hierarchy of gods
Then climb to the top
He is the victor among the gods
He has eyes all over the head
He can say spells
I like this idea
The Egyptians also formed this idea
Because their god Horus is that eye
Everyone knows the Eye of Horus
The concept is so attractive
Spread to this day
Everyone has seen the Eye of Horus
Its pupils are completely open
The Egyptians recognized
Fully open eyes can regenerate a dead society
This view is really wonderful
So if your life is in chaos
What should you do
You better concentrate
This is different from thinking
It is a different process
In a sense, thinking is the result of structure execution
I know I oversimplified
But focus on one thing
Like looking at something you don't understand
One thing I often recommend to guests in my clinic is
If they have family conflicts
The first thing to do is to shut up
Don't say any more of your own ideas
Not in a rude manner
Just stop talking about your own thoughts
Second, watch them like an eagle and listen carefully
If you persist long enough
They will tell you exactly what they want
They will tell you
What kind of person are you in their hearts
Then you will be shocked
Because generally speaking, the way they have you
Totally different from what you think you are
When they tell you
This is a revelation for you
Attention is incredibly powerful
You can also see it in psychotherapy
Because of the many things you do
In all repairable relationships
Are really focusing on the opposite person
Focus and listen
You will be surprised
What people will tell or reveal to you
If you watch them
Like you are listening
Instead of staring at them
In order to strengthen one's prejudice
People usually communicate like that
Like i want to always
Keep my opinion of you
So I want to filter out all the information that shakes my theory
This is not what i want to say
It's just that I want to watch you
And figure out what you want
Not in a rude way not at all
I just want to see what you are thinking
This is probably good for you
Also good for me
The concept is
Climbing up in the authority level can give you vision
This vision can go beyond the current hierarchy
I think this is also the artists
Metaphysical space
Because artists do not exist in the hierarchy
They exist outside the hierarchy
Most of you have seen "The Lion King"
It's like Shazu's little bird
That is the king's eye
This is also connected with this concept
These figures also express the same concept of hierarchy
Gold, silver and copper
Why gold
Gold is the sun gold is pure
The concept is
Things at the top of the hierarchy are not corrodible
Because gold will not mix with other things
Gold will never be corroded
It is a noble metal
It will not be corroded
It shines like the sun
So it is with
Things at the top of the hierarchy are linked together
The gold medal is a disc like the sun
It will be rewarded
And the ideal person
I tell you a little story
Imagine you are watching an Olympic game
I often do this when I watch gymnastics
Because gymnasts are really incredible
Look at a gymnastics show
Athletes pulsate like a poem on the court
You can't even imagine this
Their skills are so perfect
You see this person
Complete the whole set of actions
They are simply perfect and flawless
At the end they stopped and thunderous applause
They are all very excited to see humans refresh their limits
This is why our audience watch the game
Because we want to see the limits of human physical fitness
Then the judges scored 9.8 9.8 9.8
Everyone is very excited
Then the next player on the field is like
They are basically done
The performance of the previous player is simply perfect
How can you surpass him
This is an interesting question
Because these pictures show
How do you go beyond perfection
you can do it
Here is how to do it
And you know these
Even if you don’t realize that you know
The next player is a little trembling
Because the standard has been raised
They pushed themselves to the edge of chaos
You can tell by observing their plight
They are at a critical juncture
They push themselves into the unexplored state
Just for perfection
Everyone in the hall is so nervous that they hold their breath
Silent needles can be heard
The athlete is turning around
Hit the mark
After the end, they held their heads up like this and opened their arms
A triumphant posture
Everyone immediately stood up and thunderous applause
why
what are you doing
What are you thinking now
You can't even hold on
It directly captures the core of your being
Then you stand up
This is just an act of worship
You see some people go beyond their own perfection
Entered the realm of chaos
And established order before your eyes
You will feel ecstatic
Think it's worth it
Cheers
This is definitely a strange thing
Sometimes that picture expresses
Sometimes this picture expresses
This is what we want to discuss
Because this is the culmination of the hierarchy
You are not only doing what you should do
And it also makes you more likely
On this basis
The same idea another thing
I know we haven't told the story of Adam and Eve
You tell your kids to play fairly
You said winning or losing is not the point
The focus is on the way the game is played
You say that but you don't know the meaning
You feel a bit silly to say that
Even if you know it's right
Your kids look at you too
It seems something is wrong with you
Because they don't know what you are talking about
But you know what you said is right
Let me talk about the reason
Life is not a game
But a series of games
The rule is not to win a game
Sacrificed long-term victory, right?
This is the meaning of "play well"
The way you want to play
Make others willing to invite you to keep playing
This is how you win
Your victory is through
To be invited to join as many games as possible
Specifically to show
You can play the game in a mutually beneficial way
This is true in every game even if you might lose
This is the way to keep you successful
We all know this
I teach my children this way
But we did not realize that we knew this
We did not adapt ourselves to ordinary games
Or adapted to win the game
But we adapt ourselves to the meta game
And adapt to a series of potential game victories
This is exactly
as far as I know
What these pictures want to express
The same idea
There is a mode of being
Features that can surpass local competition
This is another way of thinking
Pursuing ethics is not to win the current competition
At the expense of future potential competition opportunities
Again, I don’t think this is arbitrary
Not relative
There is an absolute moral position in the world
Everyone knows
I also think this is the secret of success
I also think it’s weird
It is similar to the following view
Good at being invited
People who participate in as many games as possible
I haven't figured it out yet
The precise relationship between these two views
At the same time proactively
Before the unknown came to the city in a hostile posture
Conquer the unknown
The two are exactly the same
I haven't fully understood the reason yet
But i will know in the end
I will tell you when I know
If you are interested
There are some other ideas
About God as an authority figure in the hierarchy
Discard your religious prejudice about what you observe
Simply observe what you see
This is a primate in the picture
He is looking up at the ruler
This is what you see
It is shown interestingly and symbolically
You can see the Father with the cross
I think it means there is a kind of cognition
The person with the highest authority in the picture
He accepted voluntarily
The fact that suffering is also part of the being
This is what this picture wants to express
This authority figure holding a cross said
This is what you have to accept
This shocked bystanders
Because it's real
Is it true?
You think so first
Do you like the brave or the coward
Blunt enough
What is the limit of heroism
After accepting the fact that you are mortal and not everything
Can still live forever
This is the core of respectable quality
Why don't we assume that
This is how we acted
This is what everyone dreams of and hopes to do
The premise is that you have abandoned
The idea that you can live forever
Eternal life may be worth looking forward to, maybe not
Immortality is a long time
But you definitely want this
This painting says this is what you should be
We got the same scene as the sky hole before
That is a scene I have shown you before
This is a transcendent truth
Everywhere
Jung would say that this concept is rooted in your mind
Some elements of this are cultural
It doesn’t have to be a cross
Although the cross is a very old symbol
Far before it was used in Christianity
It is used in many religious expressions
The soul resonates with it
The picture on the right is Moses
Standing on the mountain and receiving the law
When we talk about "Exodus", we will talk about it
Suppose
Suppose we can talk about "Exodus"
Where did this happen
Above the mountain
This is a pyramid right
High to the stratosphere
In the sky you look up
What happened to Moses
This is a clue I can think of
Read Jean Piaget's book
Let me figure it out
Piaget’s view on the child part is
They learned to play first
But they don't understand the rules
Means if there are a group of children together
They can play games
But if you pull out a young child
For example, when you are six years old and ask what the rules of the game are
They can only give you ambiguous descriptions
So you found out the first six-year-old child
He will tell you some rules
The second six-year-old will tell you some different rules
The third six-year-old will tell you something different
But if you put them together
They can play smoothly
They have concrete knowledge
Concretely individual or collective
This knowledge has not been extracted
Then they grow up
You can extract the rules
Then they can start playing the game according to the rules
Piaget’s final step is
Children don’t just play by the rules
They also recognize that they can make rules
He thinks this is the path of moral development
First you can play
Then you can play according to the rules
Then you may realize
Because he doesn't think everyone can recognize this
You are actually the ruler
This is not to say that the rules are arbitrary
It means you can be a rule maker
On the premise that you know how to play
Piaget thinks this is the path of moral development
I think this is exactly what happened
What happened to Moses in "Exodus"
Moses led all the Israelites
They have no laws and no legislators
They have tradition
They are very grumpy
Because they are in the desert
They were under tyranny before
Now in the desert
Not much better
So they are very angry about this
They worship the wrong idol
Disaster ensued
Then they asked Moses to preside over justice
He has been doing this for a long time
The grumpy Israelis complained to Moses
"He did this and she did that."
Moses had to figure out how to reconcile them
He did this for so long that his
I remember his father-in-law
Tell him to stop doing this
Because he's almost exhausting himself
You will think about what happened here
I am not assuming this is a true historical story
I think this is a condensed story
Every group has a set of customs
Like a pack of wolves
These customs are being revealed
There are some godsends observing and thinking
What are the rules for this situation
What are the rules for that situation
What about this situation
Then in his imagination
These rules become a hierarchy
Then climb the mountain
He would miss my goodness
This is the rule we have always lived by
This is the revelation of the commandment
What else
Is it because there are rules first and then fulfilled?
Wrong should be action and fulfillment first
Then you can understand the purpose of everyone doing this
You say that everyone sees this as your goal
Then everyone thinks it makes sense
Otherwise who follows these rules
No one will follow these rules
If they don’t match the established situation
You just think it's unfair
Here it is depicted as
An earth-shaking human event
Oh my God, we have always been just apes
We have lived in the authority hierarchy for so long
We are totally unaware of what we are doing
Suddenly it was dark
Wake up to the pen of God
We can say that this is the law
Do you say it was given by god
It depends on your definition of God
You can start from this preset
But it is definitely not made out of nothing
It’s interesting that Nietzsche observed something else
He said moral enlightenment
It was formed after a very long process
From the initial structure to the later idea
This is tens of millions of years
Formed custom
Before you get the enlightenment of written law
What should the working mode be described as
What is the mode that works
It's a game you play with others
Never degenerate day after day
Piaget another insight
Is the concept of equilibrium
It is Immanuel Kant
The extension of the concept of universal axioms
Act in a certain way
So that every behavior can become a universal law
This is Kant's most basic moral axiom
Piaget changed a little
He said it's not exactly like this
Acting in a certain way for you
Now next week next month
The next year ten years later
Will still work
And to the people around you
And the whole society is effective
This is the state of balance
You can think of it as
A hint of heaven coming to the city of God
It is based on the idea that "morality must be repeatable"
There are many
Trading game simulated by artificial intelligence
In the artificial intelligence system
People who study the emergence of moral behavior
Already discovered
One of the most important elements in moral analysis
Repeatability
You cannot participate in degraded games
Because it's degenerating
The game you want to play
At least stable over time
If you really do it properly
Maybe it will get better
Of course this is what you want your family to be
This is what you have been trying to do
Unless you want revenge and destruction
Is there a way
Can keep us playing together
Can make this common game better day by day
This is what you want to do
I don't think this is arbitrary
This is why I think
These postmodernists are really wrong
They say there are countless ways to interpret this world
This is true
But the error is
they said
No way of explanation can be higher than the other
So wrong
This is the root of everything
The proper explanation must be
This is Piaget’s view
If you and I are going to play a game
Rule one we must all want to participate
Rule two others should allow us to play
Rule three we should make this game
Last long without letting it degenerate
Maybe rule four is
When we are participating in the game
This world won't kill us
There are not many proper games
You don't want your kids to play on the highway, right
They can't play hockey on the highway
Because the world will kill them
There are infinite ways to explain this world
But the solutions are not infinite
The solution is constrained in the real world
Constrained by our suffering in the world
Also constrained by the fact that we constrain others
I think this is the beginning of the big mistake
If you understand the meaning of these ancient paintings
They look very interesting
Recently I found
Once I understand the rationality behind it
The painter put a lot of effort into this
This is a print, isn't it
They spent a lot of time to carve this painting
They are serious about it
When you understand the meaning of the painting
These people are surrendered to the enlightenment of the law
This is not surprising
Try to break the rules and see what happens
You try to violate the universal moral law
See how it turns out
I can always see people in this situation
You have all seen everywhere
Maybe I have seen more than you
Because I am a clinical psychologist
If the person who came to consult me ​​did not violate the universal law
Then i can be sure
Someone around him must have violated the universal law
This is not a joke
If you make a mistake, things get really bad
When the system that regulates our being is revealed
It's no surprise that you will feel frightened
One thing in the Old Testament is amazing
Nietzsche once commented on it
He highly praised the Old Testament
But the evaluation of the New Testament is average
He believes that Europe will use the New Testament
It is sinful to merge with the Old Testament
Because Nietzsche believed that the Old Testament was
Accurate presentation of the phenomenology of "being"
It's like saying to stay awake and pay attention to words
Be honest and stay alert
Because of something you don't want to happen
Very likely to happen
Maybe not just you
Maybe everyone you know
Everything in your culture
Will be destroyed generation after generation
So it’s best to stay awake and alert
I think only when people are arrogant
Will turn a deaf ear to this
I think most people understand this truth deep in their hearts
When you become a bit self-righteous
This happens often
If you haven't lost your mind, you will think
I'd better be careful and low-key
If i am too bloated
Things that make me stumble will happen
Everyone knows that arrogant soldiers will lose
So the Old Testament says
The fear of God is the beginning of wisdom
During my years as a clinical psychologist
The one thing that really scares me is
I have never seen anyone
Can get away with anything even once
There is an old saying
God has a book that records everything in heaven
Ok maybe it's not a book
But it’s useful to hold this idea
You may not agree
Think that people always get away with something
I tell you I have never seen such a fluke
What I see is when something happens
Someone distorted the structure of reality
And "success"
Because there was no rebound
Then for example two years later
The truth comes from the sky
They will think it's so unfair
Then let’s go back and analyze
What happened before this
Before this incident
What about before this
Go back further
Oh, it's the bane of this thing
You cannot not be bounced while distorting the structure of reality
The reality is not developing as you wish. Why
What are you going to do to distort the structure of reality
I do not think so
I think reality is stronger than you
And I think one thing people are often bewitched is
Do you think you can escape by chance
Okay you try
You see if it works
You can't escape anything
Realizing that this is the beginning of wisdom
Something scares me
Since last September
I have received more public attention
One thing that keeps me scared is making mistakes
I know very well that no one can fault a sage
But thank god i haven't done one thing wrong
Or that no one has discovered yet
But we are walking on thin ice
At the same time fortunately
Things around us have not deteriorated to the point of chaos
And didn't get out of order quickly
Staying true to the right way is not easy
You know when you walk the right way
Because when you are on the right path
Things will become meaningful and fascinating
But if you don’t really feel
The terrible consequences of deviating
Then you haven't really awakened
This is what I saw in this painting
It seems to say be careful because there are rules in the world
If you go against it, no one can help you
So for me there is something to consider
I talked about something in the last Q&A session
Combine the New Testament with the Old Testament
One of the benefits
Seems to be a change in morality
This is similar to Piaget’s idea which is
After you learn to play the game according to the rules
You will learn to make rules
To some extent i think
The transition between the Old Testament and the New Testament
That's it
Most morals in the Old Testament are prohibitions
These things you shouldn't do
As it should be
You ask your child so
Always tell them not to do this or that
Especially when they have fun
You always remind them not to get overwhelmed
Because whatever they are doing will cause trouble
If you are a parent, you know this is a headache
But the first rule of morality is the prohibition
You have to control yourself to avoid trouble for yourself
If you remember this
And do well
Once you become self-disciplined
You can start doing something positive
In my opinion this shift
Is the New Testament and the Old Testament
A common basic feature
But looking at these images, they still seem to be prompting
Serve Tradition Serve God
From a psychological point of view
Support tradition because this is the foundation of your life
There is a book about Mesopotamian mythology
Called "Enuma Elish"
If you are interested, you can read it
Improper behavior of the creation gods
They are like two year olds
In fact, many of them look like two-year-old children
They killed the primitive god Abozu
Abozu is the head of the gods
They killed him and tried to live on his body
This is what we all do
Because we live on the corpses of our ancestors
You can say living on our cultural corpse
It is dead and not a good place to live
You must constantly activate your culture
So that it can stay alive and sober
If you stay on the "corpse" for too long
The devil or Chaos Demon will make a comeback
Mesopotamian mythology tells such a story
It's like saying don't delusion
While staying on your ancestor’s corpse for a long time
Without contributing to the lasting update of the survival system
Because of all the constrained chaos
Will come back to you eventually
In stories like "The Hobbit"
Hobbits are very kind
They are short and fat
They are not smart but arrogant
They know nothing about the wider world outside
If you remember they were protected by big steppers
Striders are the king’s descendants
Looks like a tramp
The hobbit has nothing but looks down on the big stepper
Big stepper patrolling the border
Provide safety for the stupid hobbit
But beyond the border
Chaos is forming
This is a prototype story
This is why people like it so much
That's how we are like hobbits
The spirit of our dead ancestors protects us from chaos
And we foolishly know nothing about it
We feel we don't need them anymore
This is exactly what the university is doing to the humanities
This is jaw-dropping
If we don’t wake up, we will pay for it
We have hope to awaken
It's better than paying
Although it is painful to stay awake
There was a picture in my mind once
I portray the world like this
I think the world is not a pyramid
It is not a single authority hierarchy
It's not like this
It is a series of authority levels
You can imagine a vast expanse of plains
There are only one pyramid on this vast plain
Inside the pyramid are people of all levels
Everywhere in sight
Row upon row of these pyramids
Canine
The plain is endless
Here are all the positions you can climb to
Everyone is crowded inside the pyramid
Strive for
Then there is such a possibility above everything
It can glide through the air
See the structure of the pyramid in action
This is the all-seeing eye above the pyramid
It sees the structure of the pyramid
The highest law of being is not at the top of the pyramid
But when you work towards the top of the pyramid
Obtained iron law and self-control
Liberate yourself from the pyramid
Take it to the next level
I think this is the concept of "Holy Spirit"
A form of being instantiated
I think this is similar to Sisyphus
About Sisyphus, if I remember correctly, Nietzsche said
"One must imagine that Sisyphus is happy."
If there is a rock at the foot of the mountain
You might as well push it up the mountain
If the rock slides down
Then you have something to do, right?
Push the annoying rock up the mountain
There is no shortage of rocks to be moved to the mountain
After all, this is the purpose
Let's deal with pushing annoying stones uphill
Maybe we will have enough confidence
And self-esteem
So we don’t have hatred and vengeance
And my heart is going to destroy the world
Because I think this is also a choice
Sisyphus is not cowardly
You can see this
A similar example is Atlas Hercules
He volunteered to lift the earth on his shoulders
It’s like Christ took all the sins in the world
The concept behind this is the same
The idea is that you should recognize
The horror of your own humanity and bear it
Exactly what it means
The interesting thing is
If you realize the horror of your own humanity
Than before
You will immediately have more respect for yourself
Knowing that you are a monster is great
Put it this way you are a monster
Doesn't mean you have to be a monster
But it’s useful to know that you are a monster
Jung realized one thing
This is also the magical thing I saw in his article
I think this makes him
Different from Joseph Campbell and others
Campbell once said "whatever you like"
And Jung’s view is the first step of enlightenment
Is to meet the shadow
What he meant by this sentence
Every terrible thing humans do
Are committed by humans
You are one of them
Don’t understand that the consequences can be serious
To really understand its meaning
To figure out why you can do evil
It's crumble to think about it
Try to imagine yourself as a
People involved in medieval torture
See how you can do this
See that you will be reborn
Rebirth after seeing clearly will be incredibly beneficial
When you know that you can do evil
You become a completely different you
I think this is what I learned from Jung
You can't be a good person until you understand
How evil is your heart
Impossible
Part of the reason is that you don't have this potential
If you are naive and kind
If you don’t harm even one fly
You do not have any of the above abilities
Why should others take you seriously
You are a domestic animal at best
And it doesn't matter
This is weird
Because you don’t think about the revealing of evil
Is the prerequisite basis for goodness
First, if you don’t know the consequences of doing evil
Why should you care
Try to pursue good
You need to take these things seriously
This is not a child's game, is it
This is a game for mature adults
I realized this when I had children
There is a chapter in my new book called
"Never let your kids do things that make you hate them"
Why i say that
I wrote this after realizing I was a monster
I think i need to make sure i love my child
I want to make sure they behave appropriately by my side
So i can like them
I am much taller and older than them
More cruel and ruthless than them
My evil thoughts are far beyond their imagination
If they irritate me
I will definitely use evil thoughts on them
If you think you can’t do this
Then you must be the one doing this kind of thing
I'm afraid we won't be able to tell the story of Adam and Eve today
I have watched a very good documentary
Called "The "Professional Killer" Hart"
This documentary is about Brett Hart
He was once the most famous Canadian in the world
He is a wrestler in the World Wrestling League
A good man
He comes from a famous wrestling family
Located in Alberta
I remember he had seven brothers in total
All wrestlers and seven sisters
All the sisters are also married to wrestlers
They are all children of Stuart Hart
Hart was a wrestling manager 40 years ago
This is a great documentary
Because i am always curious
Why people watch and believe in wrestling shows
Do you believe in movies when you watch movies?
This is a problem
You believe when you are watching
So when you watch a wrestling show
And is a fan
Do you believe in this show
In fact it’s not about believing
It's about whether you are immersed in the plot
There are many different levels of plots in the world
The wrestling story may not be
The most complicated plot
I'm not saying this to be smart
Plots of different complexity are suitable for different people
This is why religious truth
Exist on multiple levels simultaneously
To apply to everyone
It is difficult to build such a belief system
It is suitable for the most mature people
Also suitable for ordinary people
Back to wrestling Blatter Hart is a good guy
He fits the archetype of "good guy"
This is the subject of this documentary
It’s a bit too difficult for him to act as the prototype of a "good guy"
He manages an image very carefully
He knew that about 120 million people knew him
He will be regarded as a hero wherever he goes
Later he found that it was a big burden
You can imagine
He performed in the arena
Classic duel of good and evil
Not conceptually or verbally
It’s shown in practice
Like Thor and the Hulk
Just in front of your eyes
This is the same kind of thing
We can think that hockey is more refined than wrestling
Maybe but I said before
My views on the above are not critical
I understand their purpose
I highly recommend everyone to watch this documentary
A very good work
This is the same thing
This is a silver cup
This person is a hero in a single team
This team is the hero of all teams
This is interesting
If you are a fan of the Toronto Blue Jays
Or a fan of the Toronto Maple Leafs
Of course you will rarely have this experience
If you are a fan of the Toronto Maple Leafs
Because they always lose
If you watch a game and the team you support wins
Test your testosterone level at this time it rises
If you watch a Toronto Maple Leafs game they lose
And you are their fan
Then your testosterone level will drop
This is really interesting
Can you see how deeply these plots affect people?
It can affect your biochemistry
Your testosterone level is like saying
"Oh, my team lost."
It’s like saying, "Tonight is definitely not going to be strong anymore."
Phenomenologically speaking, this is the universe
I realized
This is true
Is true not metaphor
This is much deeper than a metaphor
The most true thing about life is
Known domain and unknown domain
You can call this the explored territory and the unexplored territory
It's true this has existed a long time ago
Early to the time when the lobster appeared
If you put the lobster in a new environment
They will patrol the territory first
Find hiding place
And build a nest
So the first thing they do is
Build the known from the unknown
This is the so-called real a
Is true from the perspective of Darwinism
We think it’s true from the perspective of Darwinism
True enough
Because we are all creatures
So the theory of evolution is closely related to us
This is the Taoist Tai Chi diagram
What it shows is what constitutes the experience since ancient times
Very simple chaos and order
Orderly existence in chaos
There is chaos in order
This is the way of life
This is life itself
You should always be
The boundary between order and chaos
why
Stable enough and focused enough
You are not only doing what you should do
And it also makes you more likely
Do better tomorrow
You can feel the state of concentration
You are at the right time and place
Your nervous system will make you feel this
This is the meaning of transcendence
I also think that is the antidote to the pain of existentialism
The antidote to the pain of existentialism is
At the right time and place
Be professional
Anxiety and pain are the reality of existential pain
When you are at the right time and place
What will happen to your biochemistry
Dopamine secretion
What can it do
It can suppress anxiety and relieve pain
Not only that
Because dopamine also makes people happy
Make people willing to move forward
This is also the basis of creativity
So not only from a neurochemical perspective
You get a positive experience
Your pain and anxiety are also relieved
This is not an assumption
Dopamine system
Which is the system responsible for biological exploration
It is extremely ancient and far beyond imagination
The dopamine system will be very suitable for you
Motivated by receiving new information
This is human nature
We are hungry for information
We want to be safe
But at the same time, we must build on a sense of security
We want to do it for ourselves
We want to do this for others
We want to do this for the family
We also want to do this for society
We want to unite the world to achieve this goal
It makes sense
God knows if you really do this
How much suffering can the world reduce
We can’t think if we do everything well
How high can we achieve
Maybe we can stop a lot
Frustrating things in life
We have stopped many bad things in the past hundred years
Things are much better now than 100 years ago
Of course it's not perfect now
But 120 years ago compared to 100 years ago
At that time, the average person in the West
I live on less than one dollar a day
In today's dollar
You try to live like that for a week
See how fun it is
What does this Taoist Taiji picture mean?
This is the chaos before the universe was born
The Word of God at the Beginning of Time
The order that can be accommodated is extracted from it
It's all the same
We will discuss chaos later
Because it's complicated to describe
When the World Trade Center collapsed
What you are facing is "Chaos"
Do you still remember how you felt at that time?
Peace in the world on September 10
Everyone knows what the world is like
Then the 911 incident happened
Everyone was dumbfounded for three days
Because the World Trade Building fell
What if it falls
You can see the collapse of a building
You can understand
What happens when a building collapses
Then why are you all dumbfounded
When the building collapsed in the order we lived in
Chaos turned out
This is really a successful terrorist attack
Everyone was stunned and curious
Because this is a normal human response to the unknown
Like facing a shark
Remember the famous poster from the movie "Jaws"
There is a woman swimming on the water
A terrifying giant shark is waiting for an opportunity below
This is life
This is the world
You will experience this from time to time
When something in your life collapses like the World Trade Center
You remember the abyss under your feet
The primitive abyss
So bottomless and you are fragile
When you are betrayed
Or when your dream is shattered, you can realize it
You encountered chaos
This chaos is the origin of the world
You have to pay attention, you have to do the Tao
To bring the world back to order
None of the above is superstition
The above is not even a metaphor
All true
And more real than anything else
I think part of the reason is
Life has always been like this
This is the law of life since ancient times
This is the universe is reality
This is the environment we are in
The so-called neo-atheists
I don’t want to deviate too much from discussing new atheists
Because I think atheists are always very honest
And their analysis is consistent
But I don’t think they take this issue seriously
I think they are
Not serious enough
I don’t think you can deny such a point of view
The more profound the impact of a thing on the screening of life
The more real it is
This is the axiom of Darwinian biology
I think the Darwinian world is more
The physical world is more real
I tried to argue this point with Sam Harris
I'm not doing well
But the second conversation is ok
Take this problem seriously
This is a very serious and meaningful proposition
Whether people know it or not
They are all playing roles and want to play roles
This picture is Marduk
Marduk's story
Let me talk briefly
At the beginning of time, Diamat and Abzu hugged and joined
They are the gods of salt water and fresh water
Chaos and order
They created yin and yang
They also created the world of gods
These gods to me
Just like the source of power at the beginning of time
They are like anger and love etc.
Occupy us from ancient times to the present
Also floods the whole world
They murdered their father Abozu ignorantly
They lived a life of drunkenness and then killed Abozu
Diamatt learned of this, this picture shows Diamatt
Looks terrible
She is the mother of all things
She is very unhappy about it
Her children killed the structure itself
Besides, they are noisy and careless
She wants to do it
She is like God in Noah’s story
Similar to the Same Work
Diamatt is back and say yes you guys
It's endless, right?
I want to clean up you
She made a lot of monsters
Then pick the worst monster to lead them
The monster's name is "Jin Gu", the predecessor of Satan
She let the gods know that she is coming for revenge
The gods are not happy about this
They are gods but she is Chaos itself
Mother of all things
This is not a joke
The gods challenged Diamat one by one
One by one
Powerless
One day a new god appeared
He is Marduk
The gods found him extraordinary as soon as he was born
To know that time
The tribes of Mesopotamia are coming together to become
One of the first great civilizations in history
The gods of these tribes
Also brought together to form a hierarchy
To figure out what traits can rule everything
Marduk was chosen by the gods
He said, "I can challenge Diamat."
But one thing
From now on you all will follow me
I come to master destiny
I am the head of the gods
I'm at the top of the hierarchy
Other gods said, "No problem
"As long as you solve the chaos, we will only look forward to you."
Marduk's head is full of eyes
And can vomit spells
This is his main characteristic
He brought a net to challenge Diamat
Besie her in a net
I think it's so funny
Because the net represents generalization
This is a conceptual summary
He surrounded chaos itself with conceptual structure
He trapped Diamat in the net and cut into pieces
Then he created the world
He created mankind
They live and serve the gods in this world
He created mankind with Jin Gu's blood
Jin Gu is the head of all demons
Colin Dyan one of my students
Helped me understand the problem
I think this is really pessimistic
This is like a metaphor for "fallen"
A view of original sin
My common conclusion on this with Diyang is
Human beings are the only
A creature that is truly capable of deceiving
We have the ability to do evil
Like in the story of Adam and Eve
We can do those things
That's why we are
Made by the blood of the head of all demons
We are creatures that can deceive the structure of reality
There was an emperor in Mesopotamia
This emperor is the incarnation of Marduk
This is the reason why he took the throne of God
Only by becoming Marduk can you be emperor
He wants to be a good Marduk
That means he needs to challenge Diamatt, Chaos
Break it into pieces and create order with corpses
Every new year celebration
Mesopotamians will walk out of the siege
From explored area to unexplored area
From the Siege into Chaos
And bring all the sculptures representing the gods
They put it into practice
Because they have to figure out the meaning
They called the emperor over
Then the priest would make the emperor kneel
Let him take off his robe
Let him kneel and humiliate him
Beat him with gloves
Then say, "Why this year
"You didn't make a good Marduk."
The king will reflect on everything
His shortcomings in the fight against chaos
Then they will start celebrating the new year
Marduk finally won
And have sex with a royal prostitute
St. George
Retake the virgin from the dragon
same
If you face the serpentine chaos bravely
You can get something out of it
If you unite it
You can produce a creative order
This is what they show through action
This is the source of inspiration for the sovereignty of the Mesopotamians
Really smart
The Mesopotamians have a profound influence on later civilizations
This huge influence continues to this day
This is a lot about
An example of a story derived from the concept of ruling power
This is the evolution of the concept of "God"
This is a thinking angle
But more importantly
This is the evolution of the concept of human atonement
One of the results of this concept is the story of the Buddha
The other is the story of Christ
The concept of perfect individual
This is at the beginning of time
"Tao" speaks the truth into chaos
The birth of a good order that can be accommodated
This is the point of this story
In addition
Show you these images
Because they are so interesting
Once you know what they mean
You know how powerful it is
This is a symbol of infinity
That's Hercules
And Lena Hydra
What is life like
What happens if one head is cut off?
Seven more heads
What can you do to escape home
Can't do this
This is what you should do
You have to fight it
Hydra is like the ultimate chaos, constantly producing small chaos
But chaos also brings life back to life
Otherwise, life will stay the same
This picture shows the heads of Mercury and Hydra
Hydra will petrify you
The middle picture is Saint George
He is slaying dragons peacefully, which is very interesting
There is a blessing expression on his face
This is a very special way of expression
This is another painting of St. George's Virgin in the background
If I remember correctly, she might be Saint Anne
Saint George is the patron saint of England
This illustrates the habit of mankind towards war
This is a muslim warrior
It’s easy to imagine the enemy as a dragon
Because the enemy is always a predator
We demonize the enemy without thinking
Then we can start a war with indignation
Because why not kill the snake
The question is where is the snake
Maybe they are on the outside, maybe they are on the inside
Maybe in this room
What's more terrifying is maybe in your heart
Wisdom is when you know that evil is in your heart
Why she is unhappy about it
Especially when she had a baby
Very seriously
This is the visual god of Horus
He is a falcon because falcons have excellent vision
They can see everything clearly when they fly over the world
This is the Egyptian god of creation Horus
I will tell the story of Horus from now on
These pictures show what I once called
The emergence of meta heroes from heroes
There is someone you admire
Then there is a group of people you admire
Then there is a meta collection of admirable people
And the refinement of ideals
I think this is what these pictures are going to show
This picture is quite remarkable
Very inscrutable picture
Jesus has asymmetrical faces on both sides
One side is God and the other side is mortal
This is the meaning of this holy portrait
A fully grown person
This is in this way of expression
One of the oldest works we know
The implication is that there is a human ordinaryness
It is also closely connected with sacredness
Is also willing to take the initiative
Responsibility as a limited life
Resulting in such a combination
And this is also reflected in a book
This is the words associated with the Son
This is the correct way of being
I think this is the perfect example
The process of a prototype emerging from the masses
I think so
I think we have finished the first chapter of Genesis
Although it took three lessons
I have to say that God is really complicated
thank you all